<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: system | Hello World]]></title>
  <link href="http://mallven.com//blog/categories/system/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mallven.com//"/>
  <updated>2015-07-15T15:10:45+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mallven.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mallven]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CPU Addressing and Physical Memory Structure]]></title>
    <link href="http://mallven.com//blog/2014/05/21/cpu-and-memory/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-21T20:35:18+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mallven.com//blog/2014/05/21/cpu-and-memory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>What we are talking in this article are concept model, differ with the  specific implement</h4>

<h3>1. Several concepts of CPU</h3>

<ol>
<li>Data Bus：Data Bus are used to transfer data between CPU and other components(eg:memory)。</li>
<li>Data Bus Width：Data Bus Width represent the number of bits that  Registers can hold, namely:bits of CPU can hold. for example an &ldquo;32-bit CPU&rdquo; or an &ldquo;64-bit CPU&rdquo;. Number of bits of CPU can hold could not represent CPU&rsquo;s addressing abilities.</li>
<li>Address Bus：Address Bus is used to specify a physical address。</li>
<li>Address Bus Width: The width of the Address Bus determines the amount of memory the system can address.For example, a system with a 32-bit address bus can address 0-2<sup>32</sup>-1（0x00000000-0xFFFFFFFF) locations. If each memory address holds one byte, the addressable memory space  is 4GiB.</li>
<li>Control Bus: Control Bus are used to transmit instructions to other components</li>
</ol>


<p>There are many articles about BUS  on the internet ，For example：</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://share.onlinesjtu.com/mod/tab/view.php?id=253">Structures of CPU Bus</a></li>
<li><a href="http://my.oschina.net/u/158589/blog/70813">Width of CPU, Addressing abilities, Instructions，Width of Register，Width of Operation System</a></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h3>2. Several concepts of memory</h3>

<ol>
<li>Memory cell: The memory cell is the fundamental building block of computer memory,every memory cell can store 1 bit.</li>
<li>Memory unit: The memory unit consists of memory cells，each memory unit can store one byte or one word, but how many byte a word represent? it depend on the specific implemention.</li>
<li>Memory unit address：the index of memory nuit，alway a hexadecimal number. CPU use this index to locate the data it needs.</li>
<li>Memory device：Memory device is a physical component of computer consists of memory units.</li>
</ol>


<p>There are many articles about the details of memory on the internet，For example：</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.baike.com/wiki/%E5%AD%98%E5%82%A8%E5%99%A8">Memory</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Conclusion: Comprehend the structures of CPU and Memory can help us to dispel the confusions about  how our program works on the computer and understand the principle of CPU addressing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
